<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Travel App</string>

    Divisions Names

    <string-array name="divisions">

        <item>Dhaka</item>
        <item>Chittagong</item>
        <item>Rajshahi</item>
        <item>Khulna</item>
        <item>Barishal</item>
        <item>Rangpur</item>
        <item>Mymensingh</item>
        <item>Sylhet</item>

    </string-array>

    District Names

    <string-array name="sylhet_division">

        <item>Sylhet</item>
        <item>Moulvibazar</item>
        <item>Sunamganj</item>
        <item>Habiganj</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="mymensingh_division">

        <item>Jamalpur</item>
        <item>Mymensingh</item>
        <item>Netrokona</item>
        <item>Sherpur</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="dhaka_division">

        <item>Dhaka</item>
        <item>Faridpur</item>
        <item>Gazipur</item>
        <item>Gopalganj</item>
        <item>Kishoreganj</item>
        <item>Madaripur</item>
        <item>Manikganj</item>
        <item>Munshiganj</item>
        <item>Narayanganj</item>
        <item>Narsingdi</item>
        <item>Rajbari</item>
        <item>Shariatpur</item>
        <item>Tangail</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="barishal_division">

        <item>Barguna</item>
        <item>Barishal</item>
        <item>Bhola</item>
        <item>Jhalakati</item>
        <item>Patuakhali</item>
        <item>Pirojpur</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="rangpur_division">

        <item>Dinajpur</item>
        <item>Gaibandha</item>
        <item>Kurigram</item>
        <item>Lalmonirhat</item>
        <item>Nilphamari</item>
        <item>Panchagarh</item>
        <item>Rangpur</item>
        <item>Thakurgaon</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="rajshahi_division">

        <item>Bogura</item>
        <item>Chapainawabganj</item>
        <item>Joypurhat</item>
        <item>Naogaon</item>
        <item>Natore</item>
        <item>Pabna</item>
        <item>Rajshahi</item>
        <item>Sirajganj</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="khulna_division">

        <item>Bagerhat</item>
        <item>Chuadanga</item>
        <item>Jessore</item>
        <item>Jhenaidah</item>
        <item>Khulna</item>
        <item>Kushtia</item>
        <item>Magura</item>
        <item>Meherpur</item>
        <item>Narail</item>
        <item>Satkhira</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="chittagong_division">

        <item>Bandarban</item>
        <item>Bhahmanbaria</item>
        <item>Chadpur</item>
        <item>Chittagong</item>
        <item>Comilla</item>
        <item>Coxs Bazar</item>
        <item>Feni</item>
        <item>Khagrachhari</item>
        <item>Lakshmipur</item>
        <item>Noakhali</item>
        <item>Rangamati</item>

    </string-array>

    Tour Spot details

    <string-array name="dhakaTourSpot_name">

        <item>National Martyrs Memorial</item>
        <item>Lalbagh Fort</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="dhakaTourSpot_description">

        <item>This is one of the major tourist attractions at the outskirts of Dhaka city. This wonderful architectural monument
            represents the great sacrificing heroes, who sacrificed their lives for the independence of Bangladesh in 1971.</item>

        <item>Lalbagh Fort is a historic Mughal esatablishment situated at the old part of Dhaka. This Fort is built with red
            colored bricks. It is one of the most popular historic places and a great example of art by Mughal Emperor in Bangladesh.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="gazipurTourSpot_name">

        <item>Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Safari Park</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="gazipurTourSpot_description">

        <item>Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Safari Park is a safari park in Gazipur, Bangladesh. This safari park is spread over 3810 acres
            of Sal Forest which makes it one of the largest safari parks in the world and the largest in Asia. It was inaugurated on
            October 31, 2013. It is located about 40 km north of Bangladesh capital city Dhaka near the Dhaka to Mymensingh Highway.
            \n\nThe park is divided into 5 major sections. They are the Core Safari, Safari Kingdom, Biodiversity Park,
            Extensive Asian Safari Park and Bangabandhu Square.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="manikganjTourSpot_name">

        <item>Aricha Ghat</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="manikganjTourSpot_description">

        <item>Aricha Ghat is an important river port in Bangladesh. It is situated in Manikganj District.The port is managed by
            Bangladesh Inland Water Transport Authority. Daulatdia-Paturia route ferries ply from this port.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="munshiganjTourSpot_name">

        <item>Arial Beel</item>
        <item>Mawa Ghat</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="munshiganjTourSpot_description">

        <item>Arial Beel is the third largest wetland in Bangladesh covering an area of 136 sq. km. It Is situated in Srinagar Upazila of
            Munshiganj District. The beel consists of many small ponds and canals. During the rainy season the plants become livelier and
            the vast expanse of water with land borders look exotic Though the beel reduces in winter, still remains navigable.The beel
            abounds in fish and during the dry season the farmers produce corns and vegetables in the dry area. The pumpkin of this beel
            is famous. You can have a tour of the beel by boats. The beel is just 35 km from Dhaka and can be reached in an hour and a
            half.</item>

        <item>Mawa Ferry Ghat remains the connector of South Bengal to the other part of country via Padma river. Furthermore, the place
            is famous for traditional Hilsa fish. As a result, this place has become one of the busiest places in the country. People
            from different places in the country come to Mawa Ghat to roam on the river, taste fresh Hilsa fish and watch the natural
            beauty of the place. For the people of Dhaka, this place is a very good tourist spot for a day trip.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="narayanganjTourSpot_name">

        <item>Panam City</item>
        <item>Sonargaon,Lok Shilpa Jadughar</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="narayanganjTourSpot_description">

        <item>Panam City, also called as the lost city, an archaeological site situated at Sonargaon Upazıla of Narayanganj District.
            This is the oldest capital of Bengal and the ancient silk road from the Bengal delta to China and Central Asia.</item>

        <item>Lok Shilpa Jadughar (Folk Art and Craft Museum) of Sonargaon was established by Bangladeshi painter Joynul Abedin on
            March 12, 1975. This is prosperous with several unique collections those someone will never find at any other places.
            There are two Exhibition Galleries inside the museum. Both of them consist of some status showing the local life of
            Bangladeshi people, for example farming, woman working etc. These are miniature version of old age boats of the country.
            The baroque decoration and the elaborated painting on the plaster of the building are really eye catching.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="narsingdiTourSpot_name">

        <item>Wari Bateshwar</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="narsingdiTourSpot_description">

        <item>The Wari-Bateshwar in Narsingdi, Bangladesh is the site of an ancient fort city. Based on the artifacts found here the
            city was active between about 2000 BC (or earlier) to 450 BC. The ruins being unearthed near the old course of the
            Brahmaputra River are a major archaeological discovery in South Asia, which challenges the earlier notions of early urban
            civilization in Bengal.
            \n\nThe discovery of a pit-dwelling is the first of its kind in Bangladesh. The pit-dwelling is a Copper Age or Chalcolithic
            artefact. Similar pit-dwellings have been found in India and Pakistan which are believed to be 4000 years old.
            \n\nLater the area was part of the ancient region of Samatata.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="rajbariTourSpot_name">

        <item>Daulatdia Ghat</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="rajbariTourSpot_description">

        <item>Paturia and Daulatdia Ferry Ghat, is the main artery of communication between the southern portion of Bangladesh and the
            Capital city of Dhaka. Here we can watch unloading of vehicles from. The Padma is a major river in Bangladesh.
            It is the main distributary of the Ganges, flowing generally southeast for 120 kilometres to its confluence with
            the Meghna River near the Bay of Bengal.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="tangailTourSpot_name">

        <item>Jamuna Bridge</item>
        <item>Madhupur Garh</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="tangailTourSpot_description">

        <item>Bangabandhu Bridge, commonly called the Jamuna Multi-purpose Bridge (Bengali:Jomuna Bohumukhi Setu) and also called the
            Poongi bridge, is a bridge opened in Bangladesh in June 1998. It connects Bhuapur on the Jamuna Rivers east bank to
            Sirajganj on its west bank. It was the 11th longest bridge in the world when constructed in 1998 and at present is
            the 6th longest bridge in South Asia. The Jamuna River, which it spans, is one of the three major rivers of Bangladesh,
            and is fifth largest in the world in discharge volume.</item>

        <item>Madhupur Garh or Madhupur Shalban or Madhupur Jungle is a large forest or raised area located in the center of Bangladesh.
            Madhupur Garh area extends from the southern part of Jamalpur district in the north to Fatulla thana of Narayanganj Sadar
            upazila in the south . Tangail and Gazipur districts and most of Dhaka city are included in this average region.The northern
            part of the average is known as Madhupur average and the southern part as Bhawal average. Madhupur National Park is made up
            of the average part of Madhupur Upazila in Tangail and Bhawal National Park is made up of some parts of Gazipur.
            \n\nAfter the Madhupur forest came under the Forest Department in 1972, initiatives were taken to conserve the biodiversity of
            the forest. According to the Bangladesh Wildlife Conservation Act of 1974, the purpose of conserving biodiversity was
            declared in 1972. 6438 hectares of this forest was declared as two national parks named Madhupur and Bhawal.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="gopalganjTourSpot_name">

        <item>Bangabandhu Mausoleum</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="gopalganjTourSpot_description">

        <item>The complex is known as the Mausoleum of Father of the Nation Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman or colloquially as
            Tomb of Bangabandhu. It was established on 15 June 2001 by the then Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.
            \n\nBangabondhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, father of the Nation of Bangladesh, lies in eternal peace at this place with his parents.
            \n\nEntering from the Patgati-Tungipara Road, the complex opens up to a large, open well-organised space containing, amongst
            other things, a museum which showcases both popular and rare photographs from Sheikh Mujib\'s life. There\'s also a small
            library in the museum. The complex also contains a small shop and a large cafeteria for hungry visitors. In a far corner,
            there\'s a small open stage which signifies the countless number of times Sheikh Mujib stood up and gave powerful,
            resonating speeches to his fellow Bengalis.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="dinajpurTourSpot_name">

        <item>Kantaji Temple</item>
        <item>Sitakot Vihara</item>
        <item>Shopnopuri Artificial Amusement Park</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="dinajpurTourSpot_description">

        <item>Kantaji or Kantanagar Temple is an eighteenth century brick built temple, situated at Kantanagar, Dinajpur. About 20 km
            north of Dinajpur town and about 1.5 km west of Dinajpur-Tetulia highway. This nava-ratna or \'nine spires\' Hindu Temple
            is the most sought after because of its wonderful terracotta embellishment. The visitors are just spell-bound to see the
            wall of the temple, every inch of which are plagued with wonderful terracotta.</item>

        <item>Sitakot Vihara is an archaeological site located in Nawabganj upazila in Dinajpur district of Bangladesh. The site is
            locally known as the residence of Sita. Through regular excavations in the years 1968 and 1972-1973, an ancient Buddhist
            monastery was discovered in the site. The monastery dates from a similar time period to the nearby Somapura Mahavihara
            and Halud Vihara.</item>

        <item>Shopnopuri Artificial Amusement Park is an artificial spot for tourists situated in Dinajpur district of Rangpur division
            in Bangladesh. There are rides, a zoo, a resthouse, a garden, lakes, central picnic center and countless shopping areas.
            Other tourist locations include Fish World, \‘Rongdhonu\’ Art Gallery, and \‘Moha Maya Indrojal\’. Fish World offers artificial
            fishes and various wet animals. The Animal Kingdom is filled with artificial statues of some animals like flamingos,
            dinosaurs, Pegasus and many more. \‘Rongdhonu\’ Art Gallery has a variety of sculptures and paintings. At
            \‘Moha Maya Indrojal\’, there is magic. And there are a variety of animals. It is a popular site for picnics.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="nilphamariTourSpot_name">

        <item>Tista Barrage</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="nilphamariTourSpot_description">

        <item>One of the largest barrages in Indian subcontinent. It got 51 switch gates. It controls the water supply of the whole
            Bangladesh rivers. Besides it\'s a tourist spot, there is a park beside it. Area of beside the bridge is wonderful, blessed
            with nature.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="rangpurTourSpot_name">

        <item>Tajhat Palace</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="rangpurTourSpot_description">

        <item>Tajhat Palace, is a historic palace of Bangladesh, located at Tajhat, Rangpur. The palace was built by Maharaja Kumar Gopal
            Lal Roy at the beginning of the 20th century. It is believed that from the conspicuous appearance of his Taj or jeweled crown,
            his estate derived the name of Tajhat. The Palace is situated three km. south-east of the city of Rangpur, on the outskirts of
            the town.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="moulvibazarTourSpot_name">

        <item>Srimangal, Tea garden</item>
        <item>Madhabkunda Waterfall</item>
        <item>Lawachara Rain Forest</item>
        <item>Baikka Beel</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="moulvibazarTourSpot_description">

        <item>Srimangal, the tea-capital of Bangladesh is famous for tea garden covered by the green carpet and also called the land of
            two leaves and a bud. It\'s a soothing landscape of terraced tea gardens, pineapple, rubber and lemon plantations. A good
            number of luxury resorts and villas have made Srimangal as the best holiday-making destination. Staying few days around tea
            estates or any resort and exploring nearby villages and forests certainly be enounced complete rejoice of travelling in
            Srimangal, beauty of the place of leaves and bud.</item>

        <item>Madhabkunda waterfall is one of the most beautiful and attractive waterfalls in Bangladesh. The green leafy trees,
            big bolder of black stones make this waterfall so charming and eyes catching.</item>

        <item>To get the taste of a mysterious rain forest, Lawachara is perfect place to visit. The well- conserved forest offers
            ample opportunities for trekking and jungle walking. There have over 460 different species of birds, mammals and reptiles
            that live in this forest, such as deer, wild chickens, wild chicken,   squirrels, pythons, endangered hoolock gibbons,
            capped langurs, slow loris, birds, snakes, banana spiders etc.</item>

        <item>Baikka Beel, a sanctuary for birds and fish, is located in Srimangal and Moulovibazar. It is a part of Hail Haor.
            The beel has an area of 1000 hectares and comprises of open water with emergent vegetation and a fringe of native swamp
            forest. Thousands of birds live here and thousands more migrate. You can watch birds throughout the year. When you enter
            the wetland area you will be engrossed by the chirping of birds. There is a watch tower at the centre of the beel.
            The beel has a beautiful view with birds as well as lilies, lotuses and other aquatic plants and flowers. There are
            98 species of fish mostly local and 160 species of birds including migratory ones. Experienced people say Baikka Beel is
            the best place in the country for bird watching. Best place for night stay is Srimangal where there are plenty of hotels
            and guest houses.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="sunamganjTourSpot_name">

        <item>Tanguar Haor</item>
        <item>Chhatak</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="sunamganjTourSpot_description">

        <item>Tanguar Haor is one of the largest natural water reservoirs in the South Asia. Because of its diverse natural and aquatic
            features, it has been declared as a Ramsar site by IUCN. The site wears different looks at different seasons to attract
            the tourists. During rainy season, the Haor becomes a sea with strong waves. In winter green fields of miles after miles,
            hundreds of canals, thousands of migratory birds, fishermen in the ditches are just fabulous for the tourists.</item>

        <item>Chhatak is a town in northeastern Bangladesh, on the Surma River in Chhatak Upazila of Sunamganj District in the division
            of Sylhet. This town is ever green. Here, people of all religions live in peace.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="sylhetTourSpot_name">

        <item>Jaflong</item>
        <item>Ratargul Swamp Forest</item>
        <item>Haripur Gas Field</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="sylhetTourSpot_description">

        <item>Jaflong is a wonderful tourist spot, 56 kilometers away from the Sylhet city. The spot filled with mountains and streams,
            offers wide varieties of experiences for the visitors. Rollıng rocks, crystal clear water of the Gowain river abound with
            fish and other aquatic species create a fantastic scenic beauty for nature lovers. The indigenous people khasi live in this
            region for thousands of years whose colorful lifestyle is enjoyable to anyone.</item>

        <item>Ratargul is a freshwater swamp forest located beside Gowain river, Fatehpur union, Gowainghat, Sylhet. This is an
            evergreen and one of the best freshwater swamp forests in the world. The beauty of this forest is bloomed mainly in
            the rainy season.</item>

        <item>Haripur Gas Field is a natural gas field located in Sylhet area of ​​Bangladesh. Gas was first discovered here in 1955
            and the first gas extraction started in 1956. So far a total of 6 gas wells have been drilled here. Oil has also been
            found in one of them.</item>

    </string-array>

</resources>
